Finding Aid for the Louis Jolyon West Papers LSC.0590
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 7. Research Files., 1890-1996.
  - 7.1 Research A to Z., 1890-1996.
    - Alcoholism--Reports (Folder 1 of 5)., 1983. (Box 72, Folder 11)
      Folder contains the "National Drug and Alcoholism Treatment Utilization Survey" by the NIAAA, "The Effectiveness and Costs of Alcoholism Treatment" by the U.S. Congress Office of Technology Assessment, and "Classification of Alcoholism Treatment Settings" by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.
    - Alcoholism--Reports (Folder 2 of 5)., 1984. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Folder contains "Comprehensive Alcohol and Drug Abuse Prevention Strategies" and "Prevention Action Plan for Alcohol-Related Problems" by Andrew Mecca and the California Health Research Foundation.
    - Alcoholism--Reports (Folder 3 of 5)., 1980, 1985, 1987. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Folder contains "Primary Prevention of Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism: An Evaluation of the Control of Consumption Policy" by David Joshua Pittman, "Research on Mental Illness and Addictive Disorders: Progress and Prospects," a report of the Board on Mental Health and Behavioral Medicine, Institute of Medicine, "Sixth Special Report to the U.S. Congress on Alcohol and Health," from the Secretary of Health and Human Services.
    - Alcoholism--Reports (Folder 4 of 5)., 1981, 1985, 1989. (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Folder contains "Alcohol and Drug Abuse Research in California" by the State of California Department of Alcohol and Drug Programs, "Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration: The First Fifteen Years" by the ADAMHA Institutes, and the "First Statistical Compendium on Alcohol and Health" by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.
    - Alcoholism--Reports (Folder 5 of 5)., 1982-1984. (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Folder contains "Fifth Special Report to the U.S. Congress on Alcohol and Health," from the Secretary of Health and Human Services, "The Fifth Special Report to the U.S. Congress on Alcohol and Health," by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, and a pamphlet "The Thrill of Victory Over Alcohol" by William Swegan and Robert Temer.
    - Alcoholism--Alcoholism newsletters., 1983-1984, 1988-1993. (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Folder contains the following newsletters: The RIA Report, The Alcoholism Report, Alcohol Alert, American Public Health Association section on Alcohol, Tobacco & Other Drugs newsletter, California Alcohol Forum, CSAM News, Bureau of Justice Statistics Bulletin, ADAMHA News, and the California Advisory on Drug and Alcohol Prevention newsletter.
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol and drug abuse data., 1987, 1991. (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol legislation., 1983, 1985, 1987, 1989. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol Consumption Data, United States and foreign (Folder 1 of 2)., 1962, 1970, 1972, 1976, 1980, 1982-1986. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol Consumption Data, United States and foreign (Folder 2 of 2)., 1979, 1981, 1983. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol consumption., 1981-1982, 1984, 1990, undated. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol costs., 1981. (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Alcoholism--Correspondence., 1984 September 14-1986 February 6. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Alcoholism--Alcohol Research Center., 1980-1981. (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Alcoholism--Sheila B. Blume., 1980, 1982-1984. (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Alcoholism--Aversion therapy., 1984. (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Alcoholism--Drunk driving (Folder 1 of 2)., 1983, 1985, undated. (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Alcoholism--Drunk driving (Folder 2 of 2)., 1980-1982. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholism--Interdepartmental Clinical Conference on Alcoholism., 1981-1983. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Allen, Steve., undated. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Altered states of consciousness., 1965-1966, 1975. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Alvarez, Walter C.., undated. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Alzheimer's Disease., 1983, 1985, 1989. (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - APA Psychiatric Research Report., 1989. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Amnesia., 1990. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Amnesty International., 1986-1987. (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Amotivational Syndrome., 1968, 1970-1971, 1973, 1976, 1980-1981, 1984. (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Animal research., 1949, 1968, 1980-1981. (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Animal rights., 1989, 1991. (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Anorexia nervosa and bulimia., 1982-1986. (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Antarctic project., 1968-1969. (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Anthropology., 1975. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Anti-Semitism., undated. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Anti-vivisection., 1989-1990. (Box 76, Folder 3)
      See also "Animal Research" and "Animal Rights"
    - Anxiety., 1989. (Box 76, Folder 4)
      Materials for conference "Anxiety: The Silent Partner," where LJW gave opening comments.
    - Anxiety disorders., 1930, 1975, 1978-1979, 1981-1982, 1984-1986. (Box 76, Folder 5)
      See also "Panic"
    - Apathy., 1990. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Arsonists., 1993. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Athletics articles., 1960-1961, 1966, undated. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Athletics correspondence., 1961 July 12-1962 March 2. (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Athletics publications., 1956, 1961. (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Attitude., 1971. (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Australia., 1978-1979. (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Authorship., 1986. (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Autism., 1976, 1983, undated. (Box 76, Folder 14)
      See also "Autistic Savant and Asperger's Syndrome"
    - Autistic Savant and Asperger's Syndrome., 1977, 1984, 1986-1987, 1989-1990. (Box 76, Folder 15)
      See also "Autism"
    - Bahnson, Claus Bahne., 1983-1984. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Behavior change in institutional settings., 1979. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Behavior control., 1975-1976. (Box 77, Folder 3)
      Folder includes transcript of talk given by LJW "The Psychiatrist as Double Agent."
    - Behavior control--Hastings Center., 1972-1973. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Behavior modification--APA documents., 1971-1973. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Behavior modification--Articles (Folder 1 of 3)., 1970-1971, 1973-1974, undated. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Behavior modification--Articles (Folder 2 of 3)., undated. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Behavior modification--Articles (Folder 3 of 3)., 1974. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Biofeedback--Newspaper clippings., 1974. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Boxing and brain damage., 1957, 1974, 1976-1977, 1980, 1982, 1991, 1994. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - "Brain and Behavioral Sciences"., 1970. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      UCLA Colloquia.
    - Brain--Hemisphere studies., undated. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Brainwashing--Articles by authors with last names "A" through "H"., 1959, 1962, 1976, 1979, undated. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      See also "Prisoners of war."
    - Brainwashing--Articles by authors with last names "H" through "L"., 1956, 1976, 1984. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Brainwashing--Articles by authors with last names "M" through "Z"., 1951, 1953, 1955, 1958, 1973, undated. (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Brainwashing--Bibliography., undated. (Box 78, Folder 8)
      See also "Index cards: Brainwashing and Hallucination bibliographies"
    - Brainwashing--John Hochman., 1978, 1983, 1990. (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Brainwashing--Newspaper and magazine clippings., 1954, 1961-1963, undated. (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Brainwashing--Writing by LJW., 1957-1958, 1964. (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Brainwashing--Prisoners and Detainees., 1982. (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Folder contains transcript of talk given by LJW at the Conference on Detention and Security Legislation in South Africa.
    - Brainwashing and though reform., 1970-1972, 1976-1978, 1982-1984, 1992, undated. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Cancer., 1982, 1989-1991. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Cannabis (Folder 1 of 2)., 1984-1992. (Box 79, Folder 4)
      Folder includes research for a presentation by LJW ca. 1992. See also "Marijuana."
    - Cannabis (Folder 2 of 2)., 1976, 1981, 1985, 1988. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Candida Albicans., 1978, 1980-1981. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Cannibalism (Folder 1 of 2)., 1993. (Box 79, Folder 7)
      Folder contains videotape about cannibals "Uomo Mangia Uomo," Episodes I, II, and III.
    - Cannibalism (Folder 2 of 2)., 1993. (Box 79, Folder 8)
      Folder contains materials related to video about cannibals "Uomo Mangia Uomo."
    - Capital punishment (Folder 1 of 4)., 1960, 1981, 1989-1990. (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Folder contains materials related to capital punishment and the death penalty.
    - Capital punishment (Folder 2 of 4)., 1971, 1975, 1977, 1980-1985, 1990-1991, undated. (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Capital punishment (Folder 3 of 4)., 1965, 1972-1973, 1977, 1979-1980, 1983-1984, 1986, 1989, 1992- 1993. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Capital punishment (Folder 4 of 4)., 1984, 1986-1987. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Capital punishment--Agendas, lists., 1960, 1966-1969, 1971-1972, 19741978. (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Capital punishment--Aikens case., 1971. (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Capital punishment--Amnesty International., 1981. (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Capital punishment--Anderson Saterfield amicus curiae., undated. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Capital punishment--Articles by authors with last names "A" through "D"., 1946, 1962, 1968, 1973-1974, 1978. (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Capital punishment--Articles by authors with last names "E" through "F"., 1966, 1973, undated. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Capital punishment--Articles by authors with last names "G" through "J"., 1961, 1967, 1969, 1972, undated. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Capital punishment--Articles by authors with last names "K" through "O"., 1963, 1965-1966, 1969, 1974, 1983. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Capital punishment--Articles by authors with last names "P" through "Z"., 1971-1972, 1975, undated. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Capital punishment--Bibliography., 1971-1973. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Capital punishment--Boykin vs. Alabama., 1968. (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Capital punishment--Ramsey Clark., 1977. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Capital punishment--Correspondence (Folder 1 of 5)., 1961 February 16-1965 April 20. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Capital punishment-- Correspondence (Folder 2 of 5)., 1966 May 5-1967 October 23. (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Capital punishment-- Correspondence (Folder 3 of 5)., 1968 April 2-1970 April 21. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Capital punishment-- Correspondence (Folder 4 of 5)., 1971 July 19-1979 July 1. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Capital punishment-- Correspondence (Folder 5 of 5)., 1985 March 27-1993 September 15. (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Capital punishment--Cumulative case summaries (Folder 1 of 3)., 1951, 1953, 1956-1959, 1961. (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Capital punishment--Cumulative case summaries (Folder 2 of 3)., 1952. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Capital punishment--Cumulative case summaries (Folder 3 of 3)., 1956. (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Capital punishment--Definitions of crimes and executions., undated. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Capital punishment--James Donald French case., 1965 June 7. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Capital punishment--Hearings., 1968, 1973, 1977. (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Capital punishment--Internal., 1983-1984. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Capital punishment--Lifelines newsletter., 1991-1994. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Capital punishment--William L. Maxwell case., 1968-1970. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Capital punishment--Newspaper clippings (Folder 1 of 3)., 1960, 1963, 1965-1973. (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Capital punishment--Newspaper clippings (Folder 2 of 3)., 1962, 1964-1976, undated. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Capital punishment--Newspaper clippings (Folder 3 of 3)., 1975, 1983-1987, 1990-1995. (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Capital punishment--"The Sentry" newsletter., 1989, 1991-1994. (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Capital punishment--Spencer vs. Beto case., 1971, undated. (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Capital punishment--Writing by LJW., 1966-1967, 1973. (Box 83, Folder 9)
      Folder includes writing and talks by LJW.
    - Capital punishment--William J. Winslade., 1973, 1980. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Capital punishment--Frederick Charles Wood case., 1961. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Child abuse (Folder 1 of 2)., 1969-1978, 1982-1983. (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Child abuse (Folder 2 of 2)., 1982-1984, 1986, 1990. (Box 84, Folder 4)
      Folder contains LJW's paper "Child Abuse and the Cycle of Violence."
    - Child abuse--Abusive parents., 1972, undated. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "A" through "C"., 1975, 1980-1983, 1986-1987, 1990-1991. (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "D" through "F"., 1958, 1976, 1978, 1981-1983, 1986, 1988-1991. (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "G" through "I"., 1974, 1977, 1979, 1981-1983, 1985, 1987, 1989,. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "J" through "M"., 1975, 1977-1980, 1983-1987, 1992,. (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "N" through "Q"., 1976, 1981, 1983, 1989-1990, 1993. (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "R" through "S"., 1972, 1977, 1979, 1983, 1985-1986, 1989-1991. (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Child abuse--Articles by authors with last names "T" through "Z"., 1969, 1976, 1979-1982, 1989, 1991-1992. (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Child abuse--Australia statistics., 1986. (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Child abuse--California Child Protective Services., 1981. (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Child abuse--California prenatal care., 1992. (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Child abuse--California Self-Help Center., 1984. (Box 85, Folder 8)
      Folder contains cassette tape recording of "Charlotte Hullunger: Parents of Murdered Children." Recorded September 12, 1984 at the California Self-Help Center.
    - Child abuse--Childhelp USA., undated. (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Child abuse--Committee on Children, Youth, and Families., 1985-1986, 1988-1990. (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Child abuse--Correspondence., 1983, 1985. (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Child abuse--Data., ca. 1990. (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Child abuse--Death and faith healings., 1989. (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Child abuse--Great Britain., 1979. (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Child abuse--Island Pond, Vermont., 1984. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Child abuse--Los Angeles County Inter-Agency Council on Child Abuse and Neglect., 1981. (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Child abuse--Mc Martin preschool case., 1984-1986, 1989-1990. (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Child abuse--National Center on Child Abuse and Neglect., 1983. (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Child abuse--Neglect., 1990. (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Child abuse--New Zealand statistics., 1977-1986. (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Child abuse--Newspaper clippings., 1976, 1978, 1982, 1985-1993, undated. (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Child development., undated. (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Child psychiatry., undated. (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Child psychiatry--Articles on adolescence., 1964, 1969-1970. (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Child psychiatry--Childhood trauma., 1890, 1967, 1969, 1972. (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Child psychiatry--Meetings and correspondence about adolescence., 1965 June 22-1966 January 11, 1968 September 25. (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Child psychiatry--Newspaper clippings., 1973, 1979. (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Child psychiatry--Psychobiology and social processes in adolescence., 1965. (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Child psychiatry--Puberty and adolescence, annotated bibliography., 1968-1969, undated. (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Child psychiatry--Puberty and adolescence bibliography., undated. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Child psychiatry--Research bibliography., ca. 1970. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - CIA's Project Bluebird/Artichoke., 1977-1978. (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Civil defense--Articles., 1959, 1961, undated. (Box 87, Folder 8)
      Folder contains writing by LJW about the dilemma of civil defense (nuclear fallout shelters, etc.)
    - Civil defense--Newspaper clippings., 1961. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Civil defense--Correspondence., 1961. (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Civil disorder--Articles by authors with last names "A" through "B"., 1966, 1970. (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Civil disorder--Articles by authors with last names "B" through "C"., 1966, 1968, 1971. (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Civil disorder--Articles by authors with last names "D" through "G"., 1965, 1970, 1973. (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Civil disorder--Articles by authors with last names "H" through "Z"., 1967, 1969, 1971-1973. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Civil disorder--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "A" through "E"., 1964, 1967, undated. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Civil disorder--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "F" through "H"., 1966, undated. (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Civil disorder--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "I" through "P"., 1967-1968, 1971. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Civil disorder--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "Q" through "T"., 1968, 1971, 1974. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Civil disorder--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "U" through "Z"., 1971, 1973, undated. (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Civil disorder--Writing and talks by L. J. West., 1963-1965, 1967-1968, 1970. (Box 88, Folder 7)
      Folder includes "Roots of Racial Violence," a reel tape of talk given by LJW at Grand Rounds, Psychiatry, Salt Lake City, UT in October 1964, "Acts of Violence," "The Roots of Racial Violence," "Three Rebellions: Red, Black, and Green," "Campus Unrest and the Counter Culture," "Conformity, Rebellion, and Violence."
    - Civil disorder--"Bibliography on the Urban Crisis"., 1969. (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Civil Disorder--Campus unrest., 1965 May 10-June 21, 1970 October. (Box 89, Folder 2)
      Folder contains two issues of The Nation (1965) and reports from the President's Commission on Campus Unrest on the Kent State Tragedy and The Killings at Jackson State (1970) sent to LJW from Charlton Heston. See also "Violence."
    - Civil disorder--Correspondence., 1961 March 15-May 23, 1966 September 20-November 14, 1970 June 20- 30. (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Civil disorder--Newspaper clippings., 1962-1963, 1965-1973, undated. (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Civil rights--Writing by LJW., 1961, 1963, 1966-1968. (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Civil rights--Newspaper and magazine clippings (Folder 1 of 2)., 1961, 1963-1964, undated. (Box 89, Folder 6)
      Includes clippings with LJW & Heston protesting for civil rights
    - Civil rights--Newspaper and magazine clippings (Folder 2 of 2)., 1969-1972. (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Civil rights--Newspaper, journal, and magazine clippings., 1965-1970, undated. (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Civil rights--Journals and magazines., 1967. (Box 89, Folder 9)
      Contains Mad comic book "The racial issue".
    - Civil rights--Correspondence (Folder 1 of 3)., 1961 March 20-27, 1965 March 31-May 18. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Civil rights--Correspondence (Folder 2 of 3)., 1961 March-1962 March, 1966 March. (Box 90, Folder 2)
      Folder contains letter from Kathryn West to Newsweek, Time, Life, Look, and Reader's Digest regarding publishing LJW's letter to the Daily Oklahoman from March 19, 1961 (also in folder).
    - Civil rights--Correspondence (Folder 3 of 3)., 1967 April 14-1969 March 27. (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Civil rights--A.C.T.I.O.N. literature on housing., 1954-1956, 1960. (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Civil rights--White House Conference "To Fulfill These Rights" (Folder 1 of 2)., 1966 June 1-2. (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Civil rights--White House Conference "To Fulfill These Rights" (Folder 2 of 2)., 1966 June 1-2. (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Civil rights--U.S. Commission on Civil Rights., 1964-1966. (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Civil rights--Department of Labor., 1965. (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Civil rights--Office of Economic Opportunity., 1965. (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Civil rights--Southern Regional Council., 1965-1966. (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Civil rights--Racial discrimination in Oklahoma., 1964. (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Civil rights--National Conference of Christians and Jews: "Prejudice"., 1977, undated. (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Civil rights--Housing in Oklahoma City (Folder 1 of 2)., 1961-1965. (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Civil rights--Housing in Oklahoma City (Folder 2 of 2)., 1963-1966. (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Civil rights--Housing information., 1961-1966. (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Civil rights--Congressional Quarterly "Revolution in Civil Rights"., 1965. (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Civil rights--"Mental Health and Segregation"., 1963. (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Civil rights--Black Muslims., undated. (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Civil rights--Reports on minority groups among psychiatry residents., 1970. (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Civil rights--Education., ca. 1960, 1965-1966, 1974-1976. (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Civil rights--Pamphlets., 1963, 1966, 1968. (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Civil rights--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions., 1963-1964. (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Civil rights--Negroes, "Black as the Stranger"., ca. 1966. (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Civil rights--Harlem., 1965, 1975. (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Civil rights--Articles by authors with last names "A" through "F"., 1965, 1968, 1972. (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Civil rights--Articles by authors with last names "G" through "R"., ca. 1963, 1965-1966, 1977, undated. (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Civil rights--Articles by authors with last names "S" through "Z"., 1951, 1965-1966, ca. 1969, undated. (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Civil rights--Anti-Slavery Society., 1966-1967. (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Civil rights--Miscellaneous., 1961, 1965-1966, 1969. (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Clark, Martha., 1980. (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Clinical ecology., 1985 August 19-September 11. (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Cocaine., 1989. (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Collins, Wilkie., 1983. (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Communism--Old information., 1940, 1949, 1954-1961, 1971, undated. (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Compensation--Reparations., 1972, 1980-1985, 1988-1991. (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Computer-assisted psychotherapy., 1988. (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Consultation-Liason psychiatry., 1983. (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Competency to stand trial., 1963-1967, 1971. (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Composers (Folder 1 of 2)., 1954, 1960, 1970-1975, 1977-1980. (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Composers (Folder 2 of 2)., 1959, 1966, 1970, 1972-1974, 1977, 1979-1980. (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Cosmetic surgery., 1989, undated. (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Counter culture., 1993. (Box 93, Folder 8)
      See also "Haight-Ashbury."
    - "The Court of Man"., undated. (Box 93, Folder 9)
      Writing by Gerald H. Gottlieb.
    - Criminality--Transcript of Mayor Tom Bradley's symposium on the Causes of Crime., 1981 January 26-March 25. (Box 93, Folder 10)
      See also "Violence."
    - Criminality--A clinical approach., 1980. (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Criminality--The Figgie Report on Fear of Crime., 1980 November. (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Criminality--Prisons., 1974-1976. (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Cross cultural studies--Oriental., 1962, 1968, 1973. (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Cross cultural studies--Other., 1965-1969, 1971, 1973-1974, 1976-1977. (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Curiosities., 1950-1951, 1955 September 24-1957 December 1, 1960 April 20-1962 July 11, 1979 October 30. (Box 94, Folder 3)
      Folder contains letters written to LJW he called "curiosities," a fan letter written to Charlton Heston, information about The Rosicrucian Order, and poetry by LJW.
    - Cyprus., 1964. (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Death., 1966, 1968-1970, 1972. (Box 94, Folder 5)
      See also "Genocide" and "Suicide."
    - Death--Medicine, Law, and Society., 1976. (Box 94, Folder 6)
      Journal dedicated to topic "Attempted Suicide: What Constitutes Appropriate Medical Care?"
    - Depression., 1970, 1977, 1979, 1986, 1988-1992. (Box 94, Folder 7)